Finding Aid for Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan records, 1830-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan records 1830-2001
Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan.
3 oversize folders
7 oversize volumes
43.5 linear feet
86726;BA;Ba;2;UBAl; Ba Out
Bishops files, records of executive and administrative bodies and of diocesan organizations, staff files, parishes and missions materials, and visual materials and sound recordings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is on deposit from the Diocese of Michigan (Donor no. 1059 ). The records have come to the library in numerous accessions beginning in 1960.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Episcopal Diocese of Michigan was organized in 1832 by Episcopal parishes in the then territory of Michigan (which included present-day Wisconsin). From its beginning St. Paul's Church in Detroit served as the see of the diocese, and the early bishops served as rector of St. Paul's. When Michigan became a state the boundaries of the diocese were fixed as the boundaries of the state. As the church grew the bishops found it difficult to administer such a large area, and the parishes farther from Detroit desired a bishop closer to their own areas and more attuned to their local needs. To address these concerns the diocese eventually was divided three times. In 1875 the western half of the Lower Peninsula became the Diocese of Western Michigan. In 1895 the Upper Peninsula became the Diocese of Marquette (later renamed Diocese of Northern Michigan). Finally in 1995 the northeastern Lower Peninsula, Saginaw Valley, and Thumb areas became the Diocese of Eastern Michigan. As a result, the current Diocese of Michigan includes only the Detroit Metropolitan Area and adjacent regions as far west as Lansing, Jackson, and Hillsdale.
In the nineteenth century the diocese was concerned with the strains of carrying the gospel to a region rapidly going through the development from frontier to a more settled state. As early as the 1840s the church began to develop urban missions in Detroit to African Americans (St. Matthew's) and laborers (Mariners' Church). The 1850s saw the development of missions in the lumbering regions of the Saginaw Valley and the mining regions of the Upper Peninsula. The problem of supporting churches in poor farming areas was a constant concern.
The major emphasis of the diocese changed in the twentieth century with the rise of the automobile industry. Throughout the century the fortunes of the diocese were closely tied to the development and decline of the industry in the Detroit area. The rapid rise in Detroit's wealth and power in the 1910s and 1920s were reflected in a diocese that became one of the largest and most influential in the national Episcopal Church. The suburbanization of the 1940s and 1950s led to a great emphasis on building and physical expansion in the diocese. The decline of Detroit in the 1970s and 1980s saw the diocese cutting back and closing parishes.
At the same time that external forces were buffeting the diocese, struggles within the church caused much controversy. Early in the 20th century, Bishop Williams led the diocese to confront the church's responsibility to labor. Later Bishops Emrich and McGehee challenged the community with issues of civil rights, peace, and justice. Beginning in the 1950s the diocese debated the role of women, and later gays and lesbians, in the church. And in a church that defines itself chiefly by worship, the question of liturgical change brought great dissension.
The bishop is the chief executive and pastor of the diocese. Sometimes the bishop has been assisted by a suffragan or coadjutor. The chief administrative bodies of the diocese include the diocesan convention, which meets annually to set policy and approve the diocesan budget. Since 1920 the executive council (since 1995 called diocesan council) has met between conventions to continue its policy-making role. The standing committee provides advice and counsel for the bishop. Since 1875 the trustees of the diocese have managed the diocesan assets. The chancellor has since 1904 provided the bishop with legal counsel. The parishes in the diocese have been divided into regional groupings called either convocations or archdeaconries (since 1995 called area councils) that have varied over the years in number, names, and responsibilities.
Bishops of the Diocese of Michigan
1836-1878 Samuel Allen McCoskry
1879-1888 Samuel Smith Harris
1889-1905 Thomas Frederick Davies
1906-1923 Charles David Williams
1924-1940 Herman Page
1940-1948 Frank Whittington Creighton
1948-1973 Richard Stanley Merrill Emrich
1973-1990 H. Coleman McGehee
1990-2000 R. Stewart Wood
2000- Wendell N. Gibbs
Bishops Coadjutor
1937-1939 Frank Whittington Creighton
1945-1946 Donald B. Aldrich
1971-1973 H. Coleman McGehee
1988-1990 R. Stewart Wood
2000 Wendell N. Gibbs
Suffragan Bishops
1946-1948 Richard Stanley Merrill Emrich
1948-1954 Russell Sturgis Hubbard
1954-1972 Archie Henry Crowley
1960-1963 Robert L. Dewitt
1964-1966 Chauncie Kilmer Myers
1976-1992 H. Irving Mayson
Assistant Bishop
1976-1985 William J. Gordon
The records of the diocese of Michigan have been arranged into the following series: Bishops' files, Executive and administrative bodies, Diocesan organizations, Diocesan programs, Diocesan staff, Parishes and missions, Clergy, Audio and visual material, and Miscellaneous.
The record group is most valuable for its documentation of the history of the diocese and the individual churches within its administration, with a lesser amount of material pertaining to religious functions performed and to the operation of diocesan administrative groups and departments. For a number of reasons, there is scant material pertaining to the administration of the diocesan office or to the special programs that have been initiated by it over the years. Some of this material may be found in the papers of individual bishops whose papers have also come to the library and are separately cataloged. These include Samuel McCoskry, Samuel Smith Harris, Charles D. Williams, Herman Page, and Richard Emrich.
Subjects:
All Saint's Episcopal Church (Brooklyn, Mich.); All Saints Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); Allen Park (Mich.); Alpena (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.); Au Sable (Mich.); Bad Axe (Mich.); Batchelder Hall (Romeo, Mich.); Bay City (Mich.); Beechville (Mich.); Belleville (Mich.); Big Rapids (Mich.); Birmingham (Mich.); Bridgehampton (Mich.); Brighton (Mich.); Brooklyn (Mich.); Calvary Church (Saginaw, Mich.); Calvary Episcopal Church (Hillman, Mich.); Cambridge Junction (Mich.); Campbell, James V. (James Valentine), 1823-1890.; Carsonville (Mich.); Cheboygan (Mich.); Christ Episcopal Church (Dearborn, Mich.); Christ Church (East Tawas, Mich.); Christ Church (Henrietta, Mich.); Christ Church (Stockbridge, Mich.); Christ Church (Detroit, Mich.); Church of the Carpenter (Marlette, Mich.); Church of the Good Shepherd (Detroit, Mich.); Church of the Incarnation (Detroit, Mich.); Clinton (Mich.); Coldwater (Mich.); Conover, James F.; Corunna (Mich.); Creighton, Frank W.; Davies, Thomas F.; Davis, William L.; Dearborn (Mich.); Deckerville Chapel (Bridgehampton, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Dexter (Mich.); East Tawas (Mich.); Emmanuel Episcopal Church (Saint Louis, Mich.); Epiphany Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan.; Episcopal Church--Michigan.; Episcopal Church (Port Crescent, Mich.); Episcopal Mission (Norwood, Mich.); Escanaba (Mich.); Ferndale (Mich.); Flint (Mich.); Gagetown (Mich.); Gladstone (Mich.); Good Samaritan Hospital (Saginaw, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Jonesville, Mich.); Grace Church (Mount Clemens, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Port Huron, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Bay City, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Gagetown, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Lapeer, Mich.); Grace Episcopal Church (Long Rapids, Mich.); Grace Mission (Belleville, Mich.); Grass Lake (Mich.); Grosse Ile (Mich.); Hamburg (Mich.); Harris, Samuel Smith, 1841-1888.; Sans Souci (Mich.); Hazel Park (Mich.); Henrietta (Mich.); Highland Park (Mich.); Hillman (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Howell (Mich.); Hudson (Mich.); Jackson (Mich.); Jamison, Andrew.; Jonesville (Mich.); Lapeer (Mich.); Linden (Mich.); Long Rapids (Mich.); Lyster, William Narcissus.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Marine City (Mich.); Mariners' Church of Detroit (Detroit, Mich.); Marlette (Mich.); Menominee (Mich.); Messiah Church (Linden, Mich.); Miller, Sidney Trowbridge, 1864-1940.; Mills, Julia H.; Monroe (Mich.); Mount Clemens (Mich.); Norwood (Mich.); Oakley Park (Mich.); Otter Lake (Mich.); Page, Herman, 1866-1942.; Pittman, James E.; Port Crescent (Mich.); Port Huron (Mich.); Michigan--Church history.; River Rouge (Mich.); Rochester (Mich.); Romeo (Mich.); Romulus (Mich.); Royal Oak (Mich.); Saginaw (Mich.); St. Alban's Episcopal Church (Highland Park, Mich.); St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); St. Andrew's Memorial Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Flint, Mich.); St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Romulus, Mich.); St. Anne's Episcopal Church (Oakley Park, Mich.); Saint Clair (Mich.); St. George's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Hilda's Episcopal Church (River Rouge, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Birmingham, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Cheboygan, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Dexter, Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Grosse Ile, Mich.); St. James' Episcopal Church (Sault Sainte Marie, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Au Sable, Mich.); St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Big Rapids, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Clinton, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Howell, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Otter Lake, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Royal Oak, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Sandusky, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Vassar, Mich.); St. John's Episcopal Church (Wayne, Mich.); Saint Louis (Mich.); St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Allen Park, Mich.); St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ferndale, Mich.); St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.); St. Margaret's Episcopal Church (Hazel Park, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Coldwater, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Mark's Episcopal Church (Marine City, Mich.); St. Mary's Episcopal Church (Grass Lake, Mich.); St. Matthew's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Matthias' Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Michael and All Angels' Episcopal Church (Cambridge Junction, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Bad Axe, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Brighton, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Carsonville, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Corunna, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Flint, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Harsen's Island, Mich.); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Jackson, Mich.); St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Hillsdale, Mich.); St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Tecumseh, Mich.); St. Philip's and St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Philip's Episcopal Church (Rochester, Mich.); St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Escanaba, Mich.); St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Hamburg, Mich.); St. Stephen's Episcopal Church (Wyandotte, Mich.); St. Thomas Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); Sandusky (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Stockbridge (Mich.); Tecumseh (Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Alpena, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Gladstone, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Hudson, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Mackinac Island, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Monroe, Mich.); Trinity Episcopal Church (Saint Clair, Mich.); Trowbridge, C. C. (Charles Christopher), 1800-1883.; Trowbridge (Mich.); Trowbridge Mission (Menominee, Mich.); Vassar (Mich.); Wayne (Mich.); Welton, Alanson W.; Williams, Charles David, 1860-1923.; Wyandotte (Mich.); Ypsilanti (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Episcopal Church--Michigan.; Camps.; Chapels.; Church buildings.; Clergy.; Creighton, Frank W.; Davies, Thomas F.; Demonstrations.; Emrich, Richard S. M. (Richard Stanley Merrill), 1910-; Gay rights.; Harris, Samuel Smith, 1841-1888.; Interiors--Churches.; McCoskry, Samuel Allen, 1804-1886.; Missions--Michigan.; Page, Herman, 1866-1942.; Religion.; Women's rights.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Adrian.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Algonac.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Alma.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Alpena.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Au Sable.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Bad Axe.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Bay City.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Birmingham.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Bloomfield Hills.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Brighton.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Brooklyn.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Cambridge Junction.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Cheboygan.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Chesaning.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Coleman.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Corunna.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Croswell.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Dearborn.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Detroit.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Dexter.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Dryden.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Durand.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--East Tawas.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Fenton.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Ferndale.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Flint.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Gladwin.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Grosse Pointe.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hagensville.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hamburg.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hazel Park.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hillman.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Houghton Lake.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Howell.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Hudson.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Inkster.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Jackson.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Jonesville.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Lachine.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Lansing.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Lapeer.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Lexington.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Lincoln Park.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Long Rapids.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Marine City.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Marlette.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Monroe.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Onaway.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Otter Lake.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Owosso.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Plymouth.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Pointe Aux Pins.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Pontiac.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Port Huron.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Rochester.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Rose City.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Roseville.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Royal Oak.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Saginaw.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Saint Clair.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Saint Johns.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Standish.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Wayne.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--West Branch.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Williamston.; Anglican church buildings--Michigan--Wyandotte.
Contributors:
Baldwin, Henry P. (Henry Porter), 1814-1892.; McCoskry, Samuel Allen, 1804-1886.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Motion pictures.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Bishops' files
  The Bishops files series contains records from the offices of Bishops Emrich, McGehee, and Crowley, with a small amount from Bishop Wood in the McGehee file. As noted above, the Bentley Historical Library has separate collections of the papers of Bishops McCoskry, Harris, Williams, Page, and Emrich.
  - Bishop Richard Emrich files 1930-1967
    The Bishop Richard Emrich files subseries includes materials both from the period when he served as bishop and before. This series should be used in connection with the Emrich collection of personal materials which is separately cataloged.
    - Background (Box 12)
    - Citizen's Committee on Group Tensions 1953 (Box 12)
    - Commission on Community Relations 1961 (Box 12)
    - Committees (Box 12)
    - Correspondence 1946-1970 (scattered dates) (Box 12)
    - Detroit 250th Birthday materials (Box 12)
    - Diocesan Cathedral 1956-1960 (Box 12)
    - Diocesan Cathedral Chapter 1956-1965 (Box 12)
    - Evangelism programs 1947-1957 (Box 12)
    - Fundraising 1954-1958 (Box 12)
    - General (Box 12)
    - James Pike (dissenter) 1957-1967 (Box 12)
    - McCarthyism (Box 12)
    - Newsletters (scattered dates in 1930s and 1940s) (Box 12)
    - People's Community Church 1959-1963 (Box 12)
    - Social services (Box 12)
    - Speeches, statements, sermons (Box 12)
    - Trip around the world 1951 (Box 12)
    - West Central Organization 1965 (Box 12)
    - Year of Study Committee 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Bishop H. Coleman McGehee/R. Stewart Wood Files
    The accession of H. Coleman McGehee/R. Stewart Wood papers deals almost exclusively with the tenure of Bishop H. Coleman McGehee (Bishop of Michigan, 1973-1990). Bishop McGehee was born in Richmond, Virginia, on July 7, 1923. He received a B.S. in Engineering from Virginia Polytechnic Institute in 1947, a J.D. from the University of Richmond in 1949. He later attended the Virginia Theological Seminary, receiving his Masters of Divinity in 1957 and a Doctor of Divinity in 1973. In 1971, McGehee became Bishop Coadjutor of the Diocese of Michigan and, two years later, the VIII Bishop of Michigan, a position he held until his retirement in 1990. As Bishop, McGehee was very active both in the Church and in political and social activism. He supported the peace movement, participating in protests against the Cold War and U.S. intervention in Central America, among others. He also spoke widely on human rights issues.
    The papers in this accession extend from the mid-1960s through 1992; the bulk of them, however, are from the mid 1970s to the late 1980s. This accession illustrates McGehee's political and church activities. Included are copies of both his radio editorials on behalf of the Michigan Coalition for Human Rights and op/ed pieces written for the Detroit News, along with correspondence with a number of political and social organizations. His church activities are less thoroughly documented. Important here are the papers related to the Venture in Mission fundraising effort and the House of Bishops annual meetings. This accession includes a small amount of material from the period after McGehee's tenure when R. Stewart Wood was bishop.
    - Appointment and related (Box 12)
      - Consecration 1971 (Box 12)
      - Election 1971, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
      - Retirement 1989 (Box 12)
    - Church Responsibilities
      - Michigan Diocese
        - Administrative 1972-1986 (Box 12)
        - Affirmative Action 1982 (Box 12)
        - Armed Forces 1983-1986 (Box 12)
        - Bishop Desmond Tutu Visit 1988 (Box 12)
        - Communications Committee 1972-1980 (Box 12)
        - Consecration of Church 1960-1965 (Box 12)
        - Council of Churches, Detroit 1970-1972 (Box 12)
        - Ordination Process 1970-1986 (Box 12)
        - Perpetual Deaconate 1965-1972 (Box 12)
        - Sesquicentennial 1983 (Box 12)
        - Venture in Mission 1977-1987 (Box 12)
      - National Church
        - General 1985-1990 (Box 13)
        - Board of Theological Education 1972-1988 (Box 13)
        - Canon 8 1980-1983 (Box 13)
        - Church Army 1985 (Box 13)
        - House of Bishops
          - General 1978-1989, 3 folders (Box 13)
          - Bible Study 1989 (Box 13)
          - Committee on Evangelism 1989 (Box 13)
          - Excellence in Ministry undated (Box 13)
          - Notes on 1989 Meeting, 1989 (Box 13)
          - Prayer Book 1979 (Box 13)
          - Suffragan Bishop for Armed Forces 1989 (Box 13)
    - General 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - Political and Social Activism
      - Center for Peace and Conflict Studies 1983-1985 (Box 13)
      - Coalition of American Churchmen undated (Box 13)
      - Detroit (various) 1980-1989 (Box 13)
      - Economic Justice Fund 1991-1993 (Box 13)
      - Equal Rights Amendment 1972-1979 (Box 13)
      - Michigan Avenue Community Organization 1986 (Box 13)
      - Poletown 1989 (Box 13)
    - Resumes 1990, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Sermons 1973-1988 (Box 13)
    - Writings
      - Lecture, Colin Campbell Conference Series, "Colin Campbell" 10/30/1987 (Box 13)
      - Detroit News Columns, 1976-1986 (Box 13)
      - Responses to Detroit News Columns, 1977-1986 (Box 13)
      - WDET Editorials on behalf of the Michigan Coalition for Human Rights 1984-1989, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Bishop Wood WDET editorials 1990 (Box 13)
    - Topical files
      - Church and City Conference (Box 44)
      - Church Periodical Club (Box 44)
      - Clergy start-up program (Box 44)
      - Clergy Strategy and Placement Fund (Box 44)
      - Colgate-Rochester Bexley Hall (Box 44)
      - Companion dioceses (Box 44)
      - Consecration plans-H. Irving Mayson (Box 44)
      - Election of a bishop notice (Box 44)
      - Consultation on Church Union (Box 44)
      - Continuing Education of Bishops, Ad Hoc Committee (Box 44)
      - Diocesan Committee for Missions (Box 44)
      - Energy crisis (Box 44)
      - Episcopal Church Foundation (Box 44)
      - Executive Committee-Council (Box 44)
      - Friends of Music, Wayne State University (Box 44)
      - INTER/MET (Box 44)
      - Mennen Williams Hall (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 44)
      - Monastic orders (Box 44)
      - National Association of Episcopal Schools (Box 44)
      - National Coalition for Women (Box 44)
      - National Institute for Lay Training (Box 44)
      - News releases (Box 44)
      - Orientation meeting for clergy (Box 44)
      - Office of Pastoral Development (Box 44)
      - Population Action Council (Box 44)
      - Renaissance Center (Box 44)
      - Robbins Company (Box 44)
      - Sears, Roebuc, and Co. National Account (Box 44)
      - Summer urban training program-seminarians (Box 44)
      - University of Detroit (Box 44)
      - Youth for Understanding (Box 44)
  - Bishop Archie Crowley files 1954-1972
    - Ann Arbor St. Aidan's (Box 33)
    - Combined Episcopal Services Appeal 1966 (Box 33)
    - Consecrations (Box 33)
    - Convocations (Box 33)
    - Croswell (Box 33)
    - Crowley personal (Box 33)
    - D misc. (Box 33)
    - Deaf, Work with the (Box 33)
    - Deans of convocations (Box 33)
    - Detroit St. Joseph's, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Diocesan Conference Center (Box 33)
    - Diocesan Convention (Box 33)
    - Diocesan Episcopal Community Services (Box 33)
    - Diocesan Study Committee (Division) (Box 33)
    - Emrich, R.S. 25th anniversary (Box 33)
    - H clergy (Box 33)
    - Highland Park St. Alban's, 5 folders (Box 33)
    - K clergy (Box 33)
    - L clergy (Box 33)
    - L misc. (Box 33)
    - Lake Orion St. Alfred's (Box 33)
    - M clergy (Box 33)
    - O clergy (Box 33)
    - Pastoral Counseling Comm. (Box 33)
    - Pastoral Development Comm., 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Psychological Education & Consultation Program (Box 33)
    - S clergy (Box 33)
    - S misc. (Box 33)
    - St. Peter's Home for Boys, 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Standing Committee (Box 33)
    - Tecumseh (Box 33)